OBJECTIVE & SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer | Front/Back-End Developer | Mobile Developer

A **Full Stack Developer** with **5 years** hands on experience in **Front-End, Back-End, Web** and **Mobile** Development. A profession in web technologies and specialize in **MERN** and **LAMP** stack, mobile development with **React.** Highly familiar with most recent **JavaScript** frameworks and libraries. In the final semester of pursuing a Bachelor of Computer Science with interest in startup, web or mobile development role.

Areas of expertise include:

Front End Web Development

Development and Testing of Software APIs

Back End Web Development

Relational & Non-relational Databases

Mobile Development

• Server, Network & Hosting Administration

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages/Markup: PHP, Node.JS, ReactJS, React Native, Redux, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3

Databases & Webservers: SQL, MySQL, MongoDB, SQLite, Nginx, Apache, Heroku, Digital Ocean

Frameworks/Libraries: Meteor, Express, Laravel, Bootstrap, SemanticsUI, Material UI, Native Base

CMS: WordPress, Magento, WooCommerce, Drupal, Gatsby Jekyll

Other Tools & Technology: NPM, Yarn, Yeoman, Webpack, Git & GitHub, Babel, Composer, RNPM

Text editors & IDEs: Sublime, Atom, Visual Studio Code, PHPStorm, WebStorm

Professional Experience

Tutyo — Full Stack Web Developer	2016 - 2017
Purrivacy — Full Stack Web Developer (intern)	2015 - 2016
Freelance Developer	2012 - Present

RELEVANT PROJECTS

San Francisco Bart Application: iOS and Android application for Bay Area Rapid Transit (BART), built in React and React Native, JSON and Flux router.

Visual Studio Code Snippet Generator: Web application to generate snippet code for VSCode. This project built in JavaScript, React and NodeJS.

iOS Cryptocurrency App: Web application to generate snippet code for VSCode. This project built in JavaScript, React and NodeJS.

Please visit my GitHub (github.com/JeffShomali) or my personal website to watch my most recent projects.

EDUCATION

BS in Computer Science. Trident University - Cypress, CA - Class of Feb 2018

AA in Computer Science. Diablo Valley College - Honor Student with GPA 3.8, Pleasant Hill, CA - 2016

Certified Advanced Java Programming, Program Design and Computer Architecture from Diablo Valley College.

Certified Udacity Front-End Web Developer Nanodegree, 2016

No work sponsorship required. References available upon request.